# Matthew Machurek

Software Developer
615-828-7853 • matthew.machurek@yahoo.com
LinkedIn • GitHub • Website

## **ABOUT ME**

Prior to beginning my journey into software development I had risen through the ranks as a Graphic Designer starting as a production artist, moving to a team lead and finally a production manager. At that point I realized I had hit a wall in future growth and with some research I learned more about software development and became very interested and passionate about coding and development. As a software developer I can use my resources as a graphic designer to help me stand out more and give even more to a future employer. I feel all the years of graphic design and management experience has led me to be a unique asset as a software developer and I can't wait to enter into the field of software development.

#### **SKILLS**

Python

React

Django

CSS

HTML

Javascript

Photoshop

Illustrator

InDesign

#### **EDUCATION**

Certificate, Software Developer | Nashville Software School

Masters in History | American Public University System

Bachelor of Arts Degree in Graphic Art and Design | Nossi College of Art

Associate of Occupational Studies in Commercial Art | Nossi College of Art

## **DEVELOPMENT EXPERIENCE**

## NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL • Junior Developer

A six month intense full-stack web developer apprenticeship that focuses on instructing junior developers with hands-on and group training.

- Build single page applications using HTML, CSS, Javascript and React
- Build server side applications using Python and Django
- Utilize third Party API's and Json server
- Version control with Git and Github
- Build ERD's with db diagram

## **Projects**

## Watch Party • Link

A website that has a database of sport events and the user can either create a watchparty for the event or join an existing watchparty already created. This was a Capstone project at NSS.

- Build single page application using HTML, CSS, Javascript, React, Python and Django
- Designed to be dynamic and component based where each component had a single responsibility
- Utilize Python and Django
- Version control with Git and Github

# Matthew Machurek

## Page Two of Two

# History Traveler • Link

A website that has a database of historic landmarks of multiple cities where a user could sort through and add to itineraries. This was a Capstone project at NSS.

- Build single page application using HTML, CSS, Javascript and React
- · Designed to be dynamic and component based where each component had a single responsibility
- Utilize Json server
- Version control with Git and Github

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## **A2 ADVERTISING,** 11.2013 - 09.2020

#### **Production Manager Responsibilities:**

- Directed a design team of up to 11 employess
- Worked on implementing project management software and automation software
- Oversaw team productivity ensuring workload alignment with project objectives using Teamwork software(similar to Github)
- Functioned as the liaison between account coordinators and designers
- In charge of hiring new designers

## Team Lead Responsibilities:

- Directed a design team of up to 3 employess
- Oversaw team productivity ensuring workload alignment with project objectives
- Functioned as the liaison between managers and designers
- Worked on advertising for the more important clients using Adobe InDesign, Photoshop and Illustrator

#### **Production Artist Responsibilities:**

- Worked on multiple grocery stores and their newspaper and other advetisments using Adobe InDesign, Photoshop and Illustrator
- Fast paced intense environment
- Worked in a team atmosphere comuunicationg with co-workers whenever needed

## HALO REALTY, 2.2011 - 9.2011

#### Graphic Designer Responsibilities:

- Created graphic materials for brochures, newspaper advertisements, business cards, post cards, etc. with Adobe Photoshop and Illustrator
- Filmed live auctions and edited them afterwards with IMovie
- Filmed footage for advertising
- Researched market trends and presented the data Microsoft Office

# RE/MAX AUCTION DIVISION, 9.2009 - 2.2011

## Graphic Designer Responsibilities:

• Created graphic materials for brochures, newspaper advertisements and other misc. advertisements with Adobe Photoshop and Illustrator